以下内容提供
the following content is provided under
CreativeCommons许可您的支持
a Creative Commons license your support
将帮助MITOpenCourseWare继续
will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue to
提供高质量的教育资源
offer high quality educational resources
免费
for free
捐款或查看额外的捐款
to make a donation or to view additional
数百个麻省理工学院课程的材料
materials from hundreds of MIT courses
访问位于ocw.mit.edu的麻省理工学院开放式课件
visit MIT opencourseware at ocw.mit.edu
好的，所以我要谈谈发送的渐变
ok so I'm gonna talk about gradient sent
今天要把它带到那个中心
today to get that to that central
神经网络深度学习算法
algorithm of neural nets deep learning
机器学习与优化
machine learning and optimization in
一般所以我想尽量减少一个
general so I'm trying to minimize a
功能，这就是你的方式，如果
function and that's the way you do it if
有很多变数太多了
there are many many variables too many
我们采取二阶导数
to take second derivatives then we
满足于的第一衍生物
settle for first derivatives of the
功能好，所以我介绍了你
function ok so I introduced and you've
已经满足渐变的想法，但让
already met the idea of gradient but let
我一定要发表一些意见
me just be sure to make some comments
关于渐变和Hessian和
about the gradient and the Hessian and
我们看到之前凸性的作用
the role of convexity before we see the
这是一个重要的例子，所以我有点儿
big a crucial example so I've kind of
为此至关重要的准备
prepared over here for this crucial
例如，该函数是纯二次的
example the function is a pure quadratic
-两个未知数X和y纯二次方
- two unknowns X and y pure quadratic so
我可以写的每一个纯二次方
every pure quadratic I can write in
在对称矩阵S和术语
terms of a symmetric matrix s and in
这种情况X1平方加BX2平方
this case X 1 squared plus BX 2 squared
矩阵的对称性仅为2x2
the symmetric the matrix is just 2x2 its
对角线它有我可以值1和B.
diagonal it's got I can values 1 and B
坐在对角线上，我在想
sitting on the diagonal I'm thinking of
B是较小的一个所以
B as being the smaller one so the
我们将看到的条件数是全部
condition number which we'll see is all
关于速度的重要性
important in question of the speed of
收敛是最大的比例
convergence is the ratio of the largest
到最小的
to the smallest
在这种情况下，最大的是一个
in this case the largest is one the
最小的为B所以这是一个在B和
smallest is B so that's one over B and
当那是一个超过B的人是一个大的时候
when that's a when one over B is a big
当B是一个非常小的数字时的数字
number when B is a very small number
然后那就是我们遇到麻烦的时候
then that's when we're in trouble there
条件号的矩阵提交时
condition number of a matrix submit when
矩阵是对称的条件
the matrix is symmetric that condition
如果是，则lambda最大值为λ最小值
number is lambda max over lambda min if
我有一个非对称矩阵我会
I had a unsymmetric matrix I would
可能使用Sigmamax而不是Sigmamin
probably use Sigma max over Sigma min of
当然，这里的矩阵是对称的
course but here matrices are symmetric
好吧，我们会看到一些整洁的东西
okay we're going to see something neat
是我们实际上可以采取的步骤
is that we can actually take the steps
最陡的血统写下每个人
of steepest descent write down what each
步骤给了我们，看看他们有多快
step gives us and see how quickly they
收敛到答案是什么
converge to the answer and what is the
回答所以Yminima我没有投入任何
answer so Y minima I haven't put in any
线性术语在这里，所以我只是有一个
linear term here so I'm I just have a
当然，公牛坐在原点上
bull sitting on the origin so of course
最小点是x等于0y等于
the minimum point is x equals 0 y equals
0所以最小点X星是00
0 so the minimum point X star is 0 0 of
课程
course
所以这个问题会有多快
so the question it will be how quickly
我们会去那个，你会说
do we get to that one and you'll say
非常小的例子不典型，但
pretty small example not typical but the
很棒的是我们看到了一切
terrific thing is that we see everything
对于这个例子我们可以看到实际的
for this example we can see the actual
我们可以看到最陡峭的下降步骤
steps of steepest descent we can see how
很快他们就会聚集到x星了
quickly they converge to the x star the
回答他们被视为一个地方的地方
answer the place where they're seen as a
最小，我们可以开始思考什么
minimum and we can begin to think what
要做的话，如果太慢那么好，我会来的
to do if it's too slow okay so I'll come
我会回到那个例子之后
back I'll come to that example after
关于渐变的一些一般想法
some general thoughts about gradients
Hessians所以渐变告诉了什么
Hessians so what does the gradient tell
我们这么让我走的一个例子
us so let me just take an example of the
梯度
gradient
现在让我采取线性函数f
now let me take a linear function f of
XY等于说2x加5y我想我们
XY equals say 2x plus 5y I just think we
应该完全熟悉这些
ought to get totally familiar with these
我们正在做一些你知道的事情
we're doing something you know we're
当我进入一个重要的话题
jumping into an important topic when I
问你是什么梯度
ask you what's the gradient that's a
新生问题但是我们就是这样
freshman question but let's just
记住我们知道如何解释
remember we know how to interpret the
渐变如何计算它意味着什么
gradient how to compute it what it means
它如何在几何看到它如此
what it how to see it geometrically so
什么是该功能的梯度
what's the gradient of that function
这两个变量的函数，所以
it's a function of two variables so the
渐变是具有两个分量的向量
gradient is a vector with two components
他们是尊重的衍生物
and they are the derivative with respect
到X是2，导数是
to X which is 2 and the derivative is
矢量Y是5，所以在这种情况下
vector Y which is 5 so that in this case
渐变是恒定的和Hessian
the gradient is constant and the Hessian
我经常在Hessian之后称之为H
which I often call H after Hessian or
delsquaredF会告诉我们我们正在服用
del squared F would tell us we're taking
将成为第二衍生品
second derivatives that will be the
二阶导数显然为零
second derivatives obviously zero in
这种情况那么H的形状是什么
this case so what what what shape is H
每个人都是2比2
here it's 2 by 2 right everybody
承认2比2这个H会有我
recognizes 2 by 2 this H would have I
采取那个抱歉的二阶导数
take the second derivative of that sorry
与之相关的第一个衍生物
the first derivative of that with
尊重X显然是第一个零
respect to X obviously zero the first
衍生出对Y的尊重第一
derivative the respect to Y the first
关于XY的衍生物
derivative of that with respect to X Y
OKOK零所以让我画的表面，从而
ok zero ok so let me draw the surface so
XY和表面，如果我在此图f
X Y and the surface if i graph f in this
方向那么显然我有一架飞机
direction then obviously I have a plane
而我在飞机上的一个典型点
and I'm at a typical point on the plane
让我们说是的，所以我在X点
let's say yeah yeah so I'm at a point X
我应该说我在XY和
Y I should say I'm at a point X Y and
让我把飞机穿过它好吧
let me put the plane through it ok so
我怎么解释
how do I interpret the
在那个特定点XY什么是2x
at that particular point XY what does 2x
加上5y告诉我或者什么是什么
plus 5y tell me or what does rather what
免费提供
does gratis
告诉我从那一点开始的运动
tell me about movement from that point
XY当然是渐变常数所以它
XY of course the gradient constant so it
真的没关系我是什么意思
really didn't matter what point I'm
移动但服用点这里这么
moving from but taking a point here so
这是怎么回事
what's the deal
如果我搬到什么走的最快方法
if I move what's the fastest way to go
如果我乘坐那架飞机就可以了
up the surface if I took the plane that
经历了那一点XY是什么
went through that point XY what's the
攀登飞机的最快方式是什么
fastest way to climb the plane what's
什么方向最快他们的
the what direction goes up fastest their
渐变方向对齐渐变
gradient direction right the gradient
方向是我如何前进的方向
direction is the way up how am I going
把它放在这张照片中我猜我是
to put that in this picture I guess I'm
想到这架飞机就像飞机一样
thinking of this plane as so what plane
你能不能问我的飞机
you could it well ask what plane of I'd
我假设我画了2x的飞机
drawn suppose I've drawn the plane 2x
加上5Y等于等于零，所以我会做
plus 5y equal equal zero so I'll make
好吧，我已经采取了一个典型的观点
okay and I've taken a typical point on
如果我愿意的话，那架飞机现在可以
that plane okay now if I want to
增加我去的功能
increase that function I go
如果我，垂直于飞机
perpendicular to the plane right if I
想要保持与我的功能水平
want to stay level with the function I
希望它留在零我留在
want it to stay at zero I stay in the
飞机所以有两个关键方向
plane so there are two key directions
大家都知道，我只是在重复
everybody knows this I'm just repeating
这是梯度的方向
this is the direction of the gradient of
˚F离开平面的最陡的向上此
f out of the plane steepest upwards this
是向下的方向减去
is the downwards direction minus
F垂直平面的梯度
gradient of F perpendicular plane
向下，这就是那条线
downwards and this is the that line is
在飞机中，它是水平仪的一部分
in the plane that's part of a level set
2个加5Y等于零将是一个级别
2x plus 5y equals zero would be a level
设置好，这是我非常业余的
set okay that's my pretty amateur
图片就是我想要记住的全部内容
picture just all I want to remember is
这些话水平
these words level
陡峭的上升或下降是一个减号
and steepest up or down down was a minus
我们以最陡的血统看到的标志
sign that we see in in steepest descent
所以我们处于最陡峭的上升状态
so we're in steepest ascent okay and and
什么是黑森州告诉我的
what's the Hessian telling me about the
表面如果我采用矩阵的话
surface what if I take the matrix of
二阶衍生物哦是的所以我有
second derivatives oh yeah so I have
这个表面让我的表面F相等
this surface so I have a surface F equal
常数就是那种水平
constant that's the sort of level
表面如果我留在那个表面那么
surface so if I stay in that surface the
F的梯度为0，F的梯度为0
gradient of F is 0 gradient of F is 0
并且在进来的先生是一个
and in in in in on on the sir on is a
更好的表面上的渐变词
better word on the surface the gradient
F点垂直，但是什么
of F points perpendicular but what does
关于赫斯顿怎么办？
the what what does what about the Heston
的二阶导数那是什么
the second derivative what is that
告诉我
telling me about
那个表面特别是当
that surface in particular when the
Hessian是零或其他表面的东西
Hessian is zero or other surfaces what
Hessian告诉我它的说法
does the Hessian tell me about it says
我在考虑一下Hessian
I'm thinking of the Hessian at a
特别的一点，所以我得到了
particular point so I get I'm getting
对于黑森州来说是零因为表面
zero for the Hessian because the surface
如果表面是凸的，则是平的
is flat if the surface was convex
向上，如果它是一个凸图
upwards from if it was a convex graph of
如果我只是Hessian那么
F the Hessian would be so what so I just
我想现在就建立这样的联系
want to make that connection now what's
Hessian与Hessian之间的联系
the connection between the Hessian and
Hessian的父亲的凸性
convexity of the father the Hessian of
的功能和凸性
the function and convexity of the
功能是什么所以关键在于
function what so the point is that's the
是的那个凸起的Hessian
yeah that convexity the the Hessian
告诉我，表面是否是
tells me whether or not the surface is
凸和什么是测试正面
convex and what is the test positive
明确或半确定我只是
definiteness or semi definite I'm just
寻找借口写下来
looking for an excuse to write down
我说是凸性和强烈的限制
convexity and strong restrict do I say
我忘记了更严格的强烈凸度
stricter strong convexity I forgotten
严格我认为严格凸
strict I think strictly convex
好吧，这是Hessian的凸性
okay so convexity the Hessian is
正半正定或包括
positive semi-definite or which includes
我最好在这里说
which I better say that right here
包括肯定的
includes positive definite
如果我只是在寻找一个
and if I'm only if I'm looking for a
严格的凸性然后我必须要求
strict convexity then I must require
肯定的
positive definite
H是正定半定
H is positive definite semi definite
不会这样做半定的凸
won't do so so semi definite for convex
所以实际上是线性函数
so that in fact the the linear function
是凸的但不严格凸
is convex but not strictly convex
严格意味着它真的向上弯曲
strictly means it really bends upwards
黑森州是肯定的
the Hessian is positive definite that
曲率是正的所以这样
curvatures are positive so so that this
这将包括线性函数和
this would include linear functions and
那不包括线性函数
that would not include linear function
他们不是严格凸出好的
they're not strictly convex okay good
好的好一些例子好的号码
good good some examples okay the number
当然，我们就是一个例子
one example of course is the one we're
在这里谈论
talking about over here
所以X的例子f等于一半x
so examples f of X equal one half x
转置X，当然我可以
transpose X and of course I could have
线性项减去aa转置Xa
linear terms minus a a transpose X a
线性项，我可以有我们的概念
linear term and I could have our concept
好吧所以这个功能是严格的
okay so so this function is strictly
当这是肯定的时候是凸的
convex when this is positive definite
因为HsH现在是F的
because H s H is now F for this for that
该函数的函数H通常为H.
function for that function H usually H
Hessian矩阵从点变化到
the Hessian is varying from point to
指出纯粹的好事
point the nice thing about the pure
二次方是不变它是一样的
quadratic is it's constant it's the same
在所有点上好吧让我问你
s at all points okay let me just ask you
这是一个凸函数，是什么
so that's a convex function and what's
它的最小值是渐变的最小值
its minimum what's the gradient first of
所有赌注都是颗粒状的
all what's the grainy in the bet
我真的要求区分
I'm asking really for differentiating
思考Victini和矢量做所有n
thinking Victini and Vector doing all n
我在问这个衍生品
derivatives that at once here I'm asking
对于整个矢量的第一个
for the whole vector of first
衍生品，因为我在这里给予
derivatives and because here I'm giving
你用X的整个功能
you the whole function in with X for a
矢量X当然我们可以采取n
vector X of course we could take n to be
1然后我们会看到如果n是1
1 and then we would see that if n was 1
这只是XX平方x平方
this would just be X X squares x squared
1/21/2sx平方和衍生物
1/2 1/2 s x squared and the derivative
1/2ikSX平方让我刚才放
of 1/2 ik SX squared let me just put
在这里，所以我们一定会得到它
that over here so we're sure to get it
右侧的sx平方这是在
right half of s x squared this is in the
n等于一个案例，衍生物是
n equal one case and the derivative is
显然sx，这就是它在这里
obviously sx and that's what it is here
sx它真的只是你知道它
sx it really just you know it's
显然很简单，但如果你没有
obviously simple but if you haven't
想到了它要求的那条线
thought about that line it's asking for
所有的第一衍生品都是一部分
all the part all the first derivatives
那个二次函数哦
of that of that quadratic function oh
这不是什么，如果我如果我做什么我
it's not what if I what if I what do I
现在必须包括我不是那个
have to include now here I didn't that's
不正确，因为它代表功能
not right as it stands for the function
在上面写的是什么是正确的
that's written above it what's the right
渐变-感谢因为线性
gradient - a thanks because the linear
功能它的偏导数
function it's partial derivatives that
显然只是一个组成部分
are obviously just the components of a
好吧，HessianH就是了
ok and the Hessian H is s the
那家伙的衍生物确实不错
derivatives of that guy ok good good
我们可能的良好和最低价值
good good and minimum value we might as
还有哦，是什么是话语权
well oh yeah what's the right words for
最小值，不，我很抱歉
a minimum value the no I'm sorry the
正确的词有像男人一样的最低价值
right word has minimum value like f men
所以我想先计算好FMN
so I want to compute FMN well first I
要搞清楚哪里哪里是
have to figure out where where is that
达到的最小值和答案是什么
minimum reached and what's the answer to
那就是我们正在放的
that so that's just we're putting
一切都在黑板上这个简单
everything on the board for this simple
case的最小f为f的f
case the minimum of f of f of f of X
记住它的X是我们的n维度
remember it's X's we're in n dimensions
在X等于最小值
is at X equal what well the minimum is
渐变为零的地方就是这样的
where the gradient is zero so what's the
最小化Xs逆转谢谢
minimizing X s inverse a thanks
什么是抱歉，这是不对的
and what's the sorry that's not right
在这里，我打算写它
it's here that I meant to write it I
对我来说，这并不是我的全部观点
didn't really my whole point for this
小小的一刻是要确保我们保持
little moment is to be sure that we keep
直接我所说的地方
straight what I mean by the place where
达到最小值并达到最小值
the minimum is reached and the minimum
这些是两件不同的东西
value those are two different things
好的，所以在s达到最小值
okay so the minimum is reached at s
逆a因为那显然在哪里
inverse a because that's obviously where
梯度为零，这是一个解决方案
the gradient is zero it's a solution to
sX等于a和我要问的内容
s X equal a and what I was going to ask
你是正确的单词
you is what's the right word well sort
为了for而向上划伤的单词
of words scratch-made upward for the for
这一点X星的最小值是
this point X star where the minimum is
达到，所以它不是最小值
reached so it's not the minimum value
这是它到达的地步
it's the point where it's reached and
这就是所谓的为符号
that's called the notation for that
点是arghmen感谢argh
point is argh men Thanks argh
我的功能的分钟，这意味着
mins of my function and that means the
这就是F等于F的点
place that's the point where F equals F
分
min
我还没有说最低限度的是什么
I haven't said yet what the minimum
价值是这告诉我们的要点和
value is this tells us the point and
这通常是我们感兴趣的
that's usually what we're interested in
在哪里说实话不是
where to tell the truth not that
感兴趣的一个典型的例子，
interested in a typical example that
最小值是多少
what the minimum value is as much as
我们在哪里达到那个目的
where is it where do we reach that thing
当然所以这就是x-men
and of course so this is x-men this is
然后是我的功能的男人，如果那样的话
then are men of my function if that's
关键在于它恰好在此
the point and it happens to be in this
case最小值实际为零
case the minimum value is actually zero
所以它是因为它因为没有
so it goes because it because there's no
因为没有线性没有线性项
because there's no linear no linear term
aa转置一个好的我猜我觉得
a a transpose a okay III guess I feel
我为什么要谈
why am I talking about
武装人员，当你们都看到它三
armed men when you've all seen it III
我猜我觉得有人可以
guess I think that somebody could just
正在阅读这些东西
be reading this stuff for example
学习神经网络并进入
learning about neural nets and run into
这个表达论点和思考
this expression argument and think
这是什么，所以它可能是一个权利
what's that so it's it's maybe a right
到时候再说吧就是它的点
time to say what it is it's the point
达到最低值的地方就是这样
where the minimum is reached and that's
这就是为什么那些话为什么呢
it's the why that why those words by the
办法
way
以及哎呀不是太大的话那
well argh isn't much of a word that
听起来你被勒死了但是
sounds like you're getting strangled but
它有点短
it's sort of short
我认为它的短从来没有人告诉我
I assume it's short nobody ever told me
我认为这是争论的缩写
this I assume it's short for argument
单词论证是一种长话
the word argument is a kind of long word
对于x的值，如果我有一个函数
for the value of x if I have a function
fF的XFI调用函数，X是
f of X F I call a function and X is the
您可能经常使用的函数的参数
argument of the function you might often
更经常看到变量这个词，但是
more often see the word variable but but
争论，我假设那是什么
argument and I'm assuming that's what
指的是那个论点
that refers to is the argument that
最小化功能好的和
minimizes the function okay good and and
和
and
在这里它现在是反过来但只是通过
here it is s inverse a now but just by
什么是F男人你知道吗？
the way what is F men do you know the
最小的二次方我的意思是
minimum of a quadratic I mean this is
根本最小化问题
the fundamental minimization question to
最小化二次电
minimize a quadratic electrical
设计二次调节器
engineering the quadratic regulator
问题是最简单的问题
problem is the simplest problem there
可能有限制，我们会看到
there could be constraints and we'll see
它包含约束但是正确
it with constraints included but right
现在我们没有任何限制
now no constraints at all we're just
看着X和我们的函数f
looking at the function f of X and we
让我删除B，因为那只是
let me remove the B because that's just
如果我删除它，则将函数移位B.
shifts a function by B if I erase that
这只是说这并不重要，它的
that's just to say it didn't matter it's
这真的是功能，使
it's really that function so that
功能实际上是零
function actually goes through zero
正确的是，当X为零时，我们
right as it is when X is zero we
显然是零，但它仍然在它
obviously get zero but it's still on its
下来，所以说它正在路上
way down so to speak it's on its way
到目前为止，反过来了
down to this point s inverse a that's
它最低点和最低点
where it bottoms out and when it bottoms
你有什么东西我得到的一件事我
out what do you get for F one thing I
知道这会是消极的，因为
know it's going to be negative because
它通过了零，它就在它的上面
it passed through zero and it was on its
低于零的方式所以让我们弄清楚
way below zero so let's just figure out
Fmin是什么，所以我有一半是的
what that F min is so I have a half yeah
我只是插入反向的
I'm just gonna plug in s inverse a the
底部点进入功能并看到
bottom point into the function and see
什么是表面的地方
what's the what's where the surface
最底层，以及什么在什么
bottoms out and and what at what at what
它最低点，所以我有一半
level it bottoms out so I have a half so
这是一个转换s
that's s inverse a is a transpose s
反s是对称的，所以我只是
inverse s is symmetric so I'll just
只写逆转置ss逆
write just inverse transpose s s inverse
a从二次项减去a
a from the quadratic term minus a
转置和X是反向的
transpose and X is s inverse a have
你已经完成了这个计算
you've done this calculation if you it
只是没有伤害重复它好吧
just doesn't hurt to repeat it okay so
我登录了s逆a
I've logged in s inverse a
在那里，那里有什么我
there there and there okay what have I
拿到
got
好s反取消s所以我有一个
well s inverse cancels s so I have a
转置的一半与-1相反
half of a transpose s inverse a minus 1
我得到的转置反转a
of a transpose inverse a so I get
最后是负1/2的一半-1
finally negative 1/2 half of it - 1 of
它的转置是对不起的
it of a transpose s inverse a sorry
那不是很好用的
that's not brilliant use of the
黑板挤在那里但是
blackboard to squeeze that in there but
这很容易重复，好吧
that's that's easily repeatable ok good
所以这是一个二次碗a
so that's what a quadratic bowl a
完美的二次问题最小化到
perfect quadratic problem minimizes to
哪个是最低级别我可以
where that's its lowest level ok I
想提一个其他功能
wanted to mention one other function
因为我主要讲的是
because I'm going to speak mostly about
二次但显然是整点
quadratic but obviously the whole point
这是真正的凸性
is that it's the convexity that's really
让事情变得如此有效我在这里让我
making things work so so here I let me
只是放在这里一个非凡的凸
just put here a remarkable convex
功能和笔记告诉那是什么
function and the notes tell what is that
什么是这个函数的梯度
what's the gradient of this function
他们实际上并没有走得那么远
they don't actually go as far as the
黑森州证明这是一个罪犯
Hessian proving this as a convict
证明这个功能我要去
proving that this function I'm going to
写下来是一个凸起的凸起吧
write down is a convex is convex it
需要一点点的思想，但它是它的
takes a little thinking but it's a it's
一个你永远不会有的奇妙功能
a fantastic function you would never
排序的想象，如果你没有没
sort of imagine it if you didn't didn't
有时看到它所以我会这样
see it sometimes so I'm it's going to be
矩阵的一个函数
a function of a matrix a function of
那些是N平方变量XIJ
those are N squared variables X IJ
所以它是许多变量和函数的函数
so it's a function of many variables and
这是这个功能你拿走了
here's this function it's you take the
明确的矩阵的决定因素
determinant of the matrix that's clearly
所有N平方的函数
a function of all the N squared
变量然后你取日志
variables then you take the log of the
决定因素并加上减号
determinant and put in a minus sign
因为我们想要凸起的那个转动
because we want convex that that turns
是一个凸函数甚至是
out to be a convex function and even to
只需检查两个两个
just check that for two by two
两个两个你有四个
well for two by two you have four
变量，因为它是两个两个
variables because it's a two by two
矩阵，我们也许可以检查它的
matrix we could maybe check it for a
对称矩阵我向下移动到三个
symmetric matrix I move down to three
变量，但我会很高兴任何人
variables but it's I'd be glad anybody
谁也有雄心壮志，不知道为什么要登录
who's ambitious too to see why that log
行列式是一个非凡的功能
determinant is is a remarkable function
让我看看我认为我认为它是
and let me see I think I I think it is
使得散热器的梯度也
so the gradient of that sink is also
该功能我的惊人的梯度
amazing the gradient of that function I
意思是我有一个高峰，所以我不写
mean I've got a peak so I don't write a
这是对的错误事实，所以
right to wrong fact here yep so the
该函数的偏导数是
partial derivatives of that function are
这些条目是项
the entries of these are the entries of
一个逆
of a inverse
那就是X逆
that's the of X inverse
是的，那就像哇那样做了
yeah that that's like wow where did that
来自好吧
come from okay
它可能是-当然是条目是的
it might be - the entries of course yeah
是的，所以我们有N平方功能
yeah so we've got N squared function so
想想那是什么典型的
think of the well what is a typical
进入X逆是什么的
entry in in X inverse what is the
典型的X逆IJ只是要记住
typical X inverse IJ just to remember
那一点非常老式的线性
that bit of pretty old-fashioned linear
代数反转的条目
algebra the entries of the inverse
矩阵
matrix
我敢肯定-除以什么
I'm sure - divided by what the
确定这是我们所知道的一件事
determinate that's the one thing we know
这就是我们记录日志的原因
and that's the reason we take the log
因为当你采取一个衍生物
because when you take derivatives of a
记录你将确定X的内容
log you that will put determine of X in
分母然后是分子
the denominator and then the numerator
将是的衍生物
will be the derivatives of the
决定性的X哦
determinant of X Oh
我们可以得到任何想法还有的
can we get any idea what there are the
我的决定因素的衍生物哦
derivatives of the determinants oh my
天啊好的
god okay
所以，到目前为止，你和我在一起
so you with me so far this is gonna be
决定因素的衍生物
derivatives of determinants respect of
所有这些变量由分割
all these variables divided by the
决定因素，因为这是日志
determinant because that's what the log
当我拿走时，这是正确的
achieved right so when I take the
事物日志的衍生物
derivative of the log of something the
连锁规则说采取衍生物
chain rule says take the derivative of
因为那个东西除了
that since of that something divided by
行列式向量除以
determinant vector divided by the
X的功能决定因素那么什么
function determinant of X okay so what
什么是决定因素的衍生物
what's the derivative of the determinant
矩阵相对于它的一个
of a matrix with respect to its one one
进入是肯定这是疯了但是
entry yes sure this is this is crazy but
它的疯狂到做这一点，但它的
it's crazy to be doing this but it's
健康还好
healthy okay so
好的，所以我有一个矩阵XDeltaXX11
okay so I have a matrix X Delta X X 1 1
X1n所以2xn1xnnok，我是什么
X 1 n so 2 xn 1 xn n ok and what am I
寻找我在寻找，对于
looking for I'm looking for that for the
我想要的那些衍生物
derivatives of that do I want the
决定因素是这样的衍生物
derivatives of the determinants yes so
什么是X的衍生物
what's the derivative of X of the
关于他们的第一个决定因素
determinant with respect to their first
等于我怎么能弄明白我是不是
equals what how can I figure out if I
改变所以这就要求我这样做
change so what's this asking me to do
它要我用Delta改变X11
it's asking me to change X 1 1 by Delta
X，看看有什么变化
X and see what's the change in the
决定性的权利是决定的
determinant right that's what determines
这就是衍生品的变化X11
that's what derivatives are change X 1 1
一点点的多少做多少钱
a little bit how much did how much did
决定性的变化和看到的方式
the determinant change and what see how
做什么有决定因素
do i what what has the determinant of
整个矩阵与X11有关
the whole matrix got to do with X 1 1
你还记得，有一个公式
you remember that there's a formula for
决定因素所以我需要这个事实
determinants so I need that fact the
X的行列式是X11次
determinant of X is X 1 1 times
事情就是这样
something and it's that it's that
我真想知道的事情
something that I really want to know
加上X1/2倍的其他东西加
plus X 1/2 times others something plus
加上第一排的时间
plus say along the first row times
另外一件事是什么因素
another something what are these factors
即乘以XS给予
that multiply the XS to give the
决定因素给出的是线性的
determinant what that gives is a linear
第一行时间的组合
combination of the first row times
某些因素给出了决定因素
certain factors gives the determinant
和我怎么知道会有
and how do I know that there will be
因为这些因素的根本
such factors because the fundamental
决定因素的属性就是它
property of the determinant is that it's
在第1行线性的，如果我不乱用
linear in Row 1 if I don't mess with
其他行是Rho的线性函数
other rows it's a linear function of Rho
Rho1所以它是如何
of Rho 1 so it is how
形式X11次和什么
the form X 1 1 times something and what
这是决定因素的东西
is that something the determinant of the
这就是X11乘以的时候
of this so what is X 1 1 multiply when
你计算决定因素X11不会
you compute determinants X 1 1 will not
在其行中乘以任何其他人
multiply any other guys in its row
因为从来没有你永远不会
because you never you never are
在同一行中乘以2个X.
multiplying 2 X's in the same same row
X11是同一列
or the same column what X 1 1 is
事实上，所有这些人都成倍增加
multiplying are all these guys in fact
事实证明这是决定因素
it turns out to be it's the determinant
所以这就是这样，这叫做什么
so this is so and what is this called
那是我的一个较小的决定因素
that that one smaller determinant that I
扔掉第一排和
get by throwing away the first row and
它被称为第一列
first column it's called
当一个未成年人好的时候，未成年人是好的
when one minor is good yes minor is good
我说有两个字
I was saying there are two words that
可以使用次要和辅助因素是和
can be used minor and cofactor yeah and
这是什么意思我如何计算它
what is it I mean how do i compute it
没有什么，这是一个数量
wasn't what is the number this is a
号和它的那就是它只是一个
number and it's it's that it's just a
数字，但我想到的可能是什么
number but what maybe I think of the
我觉得这个决定因素很小
minor as this determinant maybe I think
作为这个较小的矩阵和未成年人
of the minor as this smaller matrix and
辅助因子是决定因素
the cofactor which is the determinant of
未成年人，有一个加号或减号
the minor and there's a plus or minus
关于决定因素的一切都有
everything about determinants there's a
有一个加号或减号的选择
there's a there's a plus or minus choice
要做，我们不会不去
to be made and we won't we're not going
担心这一点
to worry about that
但无论如何，所以它是我的辅助因素
but so anyway so so it's the cofactor I
意味着太阳能称它为c11，所以那就是
mean solar call it c11 and and so that's
决定因素的公式
the formula for the determinant
这是一个辅助因子扩张
that's the cofactor expansion of a
行列式
determinant
好的，这将连接到这个
okay and that will connect back to this
惊人的事实是，梯度是
amazing fact that the gradient is the
X逆的条目因为逆
entries of X inverse because the inverse
是辅因子的比例来决定的
is the ratio of cofactor to determine so
X逆11是那个辅助因子
X inverse 1 1 is that cofactor over the
行列式所以这就是反正这个地方
determinant so that's where this anyway
我只是提到这一点
I'm just mentioning that as a as a very
凸函数的有趣例子
interesting example of a convex function
好的，我会留下那只是为了喜欢
ok I'll leave that that's just for like
教育好现在我准备去上班了
education ok now I'm ready to go to work
在梯度下降所以实际上
on on gradient descent so so actually
本课程的其余部分和周五的
the rest of this class and Friday's
关于梯度下降的课程非常
class about gradient descent are very
1806年的基本部分
fundamental parts of this of the of 1806
5这将是我们的一个例子
5 and that will be one of our examples
然后这里的一般情况确定没问题
and then the general case here ok ok so
我正在使用它
I'm using this
我不打算这会很有趣
I'm not going to it would be interesting
尽量减少那件事，但我们不是
to minimize that thing but we're not
去那里让我们隐藏它所以我们不这样做
going there let's hide it so so we don't
再次看到它，我将与之合作
see it again and I'll work with that
例如ok，所以这里是渐变
example ok so here's here's gradient
降落
descent
是XK加1是XK减去SK的步骤
is XK plus 1 is XK minus SK the step
大小乘以X的渐变为X好
size times the gradient of s at X okay
所以唯一剩下的东西需要我们
so the only thing left that requires us
输入一些决策是
to input some decision-making is the
步长我们可以采取的学习率
step size the learning rate we can take
如果我们采取太大的a，它就是不变的
it as constant if we take too big a
学习率会让事情发生变化
learning rate the thing will oscillate
到处都是它的地方
all over the place and where it's a
如果我们学习太少，那就是灾难
disaster if we take too small a learning
速度太小步骤是什么问题
rate too small steps what's the matter
这需要太长时间
with that takes too long takes too long
所以我们的问题是要做到这一点
so we the problem is to get it just
正确和一种你可以说得到的方式
right and one way that you could say get
它是正确的想到优化
it right would be to think of optimize
当然选择最佳SK
choose the optimal SK of course that
花费的时间比决定SK的时间要长
takes longer than just deciding an SK in
推进这是人们所做的事情
advance which is what people do so I
认为人们所做的事情真的很重要
think what people do is on really big
问题是SK估计a
problems is take an SK estimate a
合适的SK，然后用它去了
suitable SK and then go with it for a
然后回头看看是不是
while and then look back to see was it
如果它太大他们会看到
if it was too big they'll see
在你知道这将是振荡
oscillations in the you know it'll be
整个地方或当然都在弹跳
bouncing all over the place or of course
一个确切的行搜索，所以你看到了
an exact line search so you see that
这个表达通常是一个确切的线
this expression often an exact line
搜索选择SK来制作我的功能f
search choose SK to make my function f
在XK加1线上的最小值
at XK plus 1 a minimum on the line on
在他们的搜索线上这个
the on their search line this in the
搜索最少的
search a lot minimum in the
在搜索中直接搜索
in the search direct the search
方向由渐变给出
Direction is given by the gradient
这就是我们改变这个方向的方向
that's the direction we're moving this
是我们移动的距离还是a
is the distance we're moving or a
衡量我们正在移动的距离
measure of the distance we're moving and
一个精确的搜索将继续
an exact search would be to go along
如果我有凸函数那么
there if I have a convex function then
随着我的增加，我沿着这条线移动
as I move along this line as I increase
SK我会看到该功能开始下降
SK I'll see the function start down
因为渐变负梯度
because the gradient negative gradient
意味着向下，但在某些时候它会转向
means down but at some point it'll turn
再次和那个精确的线搜索
up again and that an exact line search
会找到那一点并停在那里
would find that point and stop there
好吧，这并不意味着我们你知道吗
okay that doesn't mean we would you know
我们将在这个例子中看到我们在哪里
we will see in this example where we
将完全搜索一个
will do exactly searches that for a
B值很小，速度极慢
small value of B it's extremely slow
条件号控制
that the condition number controls the
速度真的是我的信息
speed that's really what my message will
只是在最后一分钟和下一分钟
be just in these last minute and next
时间关键的讲座
time the sort of key lecture on on
梯度下降确定如此确切的线
gradient descent ok so an exact line
搜索将是那样的
search would be that so what a
回溯线搜索回溯
backtracking line search backtracking
将是一个固定的s，如1然后
would be take a fixed s like 1 and then
准备来向后把它
be prepared to come backwards take it
减少一半，看看你得到了什么
take cut back by half see what you get
那时减少了一半
at that point cut back by half of that
到原来步骤的四分之一看
to a quarter of the original step see
那是什么
what that is
当你如果你那么充实
and when you if your so the the full
步骤可能会带你回到
step might have taken you back to the
半途向前中途向上扫
upward sweep halfway halfway forward
可能仍然在向上扫威力
might still be on the upward sweep might
可能是太多，但这样出尔反尔
might be too much but so backtracking
削减了
cuts the
步长大小并检查直到
step size in pieces and and checks until
所以不是一半而不是季度
it so so so s not half of s not quarter
s不是或明显不同
of s not or obviously a different
参数不是平方而不是
parameter a s not a squared s not and so
直到你对此感到满意为止
on until you're satisfied with with that
一步好，那当然有很多
step okay and there of course many many
改进我们谈论的是大事
refinements we're talking about the big
每个人都发现的算法
algorithm here that everybody finds has
根据它们的功能具有
depending on their function has
与还好还好如此不同的经历
different experiences with okay okay so
这是我的这里是我的基本问题
here's my here's my fundamental question
如果我想到一条确切的线怎么办？
what if I do to think of an exact line
搜索减少了多少
search how much does that reduce the
功能减少了多少
function how much does that reduce the
功能，这真的是什么
function so that's really what the
界定，我想，有多少是不
bounds that I want or how much does that
减少功能，它会
reduce the function and it will will
将看到减少涉及
will see that the reduction involves
他们的条件数M超过N，为什么呢
their condition number M over N so why
我不要先看看这个例子
don't I turn to the example first and
然后我们知道确切的地方
then where the where we know exact
答案给了我们一个基础
answers that gives us a basis for
比较，然后我们就是我们的
comparison and we're then we're then our
群众目标是证明得到的确是一定的
mass goal is prove get s did bounds on
与我们匹配的F的大小
the size of F that that match what we
准确地看那个我们的例子
see exactly in that example where we
我们知道我们所知道的一切
know everything we know that we know the
梯度我们知道Hessian就是这样
gradient we know the Hessian it's that
矩阵我们知道条件数等等
matrix we know the condition number so
如果我从x0y0点开始会发生什么
what happens if I start at a point x0 y0
在我的表面上对不起我是什么
that's on my surface sorry what do I
我想在这里做，是的，我明白了
want to do here that yeah I take a point
x0y0，好的，所以这里是这里的
x0 y0 and okay so here here's the here's
新的XYk加1是XYK减去S
the new XY k plus 1 is X Y K minus the S
我可以计算的次数
times of which I can compute times the
F的梯度所以我要投入
gradient of F so I'm going to put in
F的渐变这里的渐变是什么
gradient of F what is the gradient here
梯度是衍生物的关系
the gradient the derivative with respect
到X所以我有一个2x好，并成为Y.
to X so I have a 2x okay and to be Y
好吧，那是我的，这就是
okay right that's my and this is the
步长可以和这个小
step size okay and for this small
我们要得到这样的问题
problem where we're going to get such a
揭示答案我会选择确切的
revealing answer I'm gonna choose exact
线搜索我会选择最好的
line search I'm going to choose the best
XK好的，答案是什么让我
XK okay and what's the answer so let me
我只是想告诉你什么
I just want to tell you what the
迭代是针对那个特定的
iterations are for that particular
功能从x0y0开始启动
function starting at x0 y0 start start
x0y0而我还没有这样做
x0 y0 and I haven't done this
计算自己它取自
calculation myself it's taken from the
斯蒂芬博伊德和范登伯格的书
book by Stephen Boyd and Vandenberg
当然称为凸优化
called convex optimization of course
他们没有不是第一个这样做
they didn't weren't the first to do this
不管怎么说，我很乐意提及
either but that's a I'm happy to mention
那本书凸优化和
that book convex optimization and
斯蒂芬·博伊德将在校园这个
Stephen Boyd will be on campus this
春天实际上是四月份的三个
spring actually in in April for three
讲座
lectures
这是四月也许没关系
this is April maybe yeah okay
所以这个月是两三个星期
so it's this month in two or three weeks
我会告诉你关于那么好的事情
and I'll tell you about that so okay so
这里有XChes和
here are the here are the X Ches and the
ycase和F以及函数值
y case and the F and the function values
好的
okay
所以XK所以我要去哪里开始
so XK so where am I going to start yep
所以我从X0y0开始
so I'm starting from the point X 0 y 0
等于B，结果是什么
equal B what it turns out that'll make
我们的公式非常方便x0y0
our formulas very convenient x0 y0
等于一个b1好，所以好，所以XK是B次
equals a b1 good so ok so XK is B times
关键比B减去B超过B加1到
the key ratio B minus 1 over B plus 1 to
K幂和YK碰巧是一个
the K power and YK happens to be one
可能只是它具有相同的比例
might it's just it has this same ratio
我的函数f具有相同的比率-
and my function f has the same ratio -
这是FK具有相同的比率1减去B.
this is FK has that same ratio 1 minus B
超过1加B到K次f0那是
over 1 plus B to the K times f0 that's
我的那是美丽的配方
my that's the beautiful formula that
我们要把它当作最好的
we're we're gonna take as the best
例如可能让我们看到它K.
example possible let's just see it K
等于0我有XK4月4日YK41
equals 0 I have XK april-b YK 4 1
服务于b-1并告诉我
be serving a b-1 and that tells me the
它的功能下降率
rate of decrease of the function it's
同样的比例所以我在学习什么
the same ratio so what am i learning
从这个例子
from this example
跳出来的是这个比例1
what's jumping out is that this ratio 1
减去B超过1加B是至关重要的
minus B over 1 plus B is is crucial
这就是如果B是大的话
that's that that's the if B is large if
如果B为B，则B接近1，该比率较小
B is near 1 that ratio is small if B is
接近1，接近0比2和我
near 1 that's near 0 over 2 and I
快速收敛完全没问题
converge quickly no problem at all
但是如果B接近于0，如果是我的话
but if B is near 0 if it's if my
条件数是坏的所以不好的情况
condition number is bad so the bad case
硬案例是小B加1B是
the hard case is small B plus 1 B is
这个比例非常接近1所以我得到了
small that ratio is very near 1 so I get
它低于1，比率低于1，所以我
it's below 1 the ratio is below 1 so I'm
收敛我会收敛
getting convergence I do get convergence
我确实走下坡路但发生的事情是我
I do go downhill but what happens is I
在我走之前不要走得很远
don't go downhill very far until I'm
后面又回到了上坡，所以
back headed back uphill again so the the
为此绘制的图片让我
the picture to draw for this let me
将图片更改为图片中的图片
change that picture to a picture in the
水平的XY平面设置是的
XY plane of the level sets yeah so the
图片真的要看是在XY平面上
picture really to see is in the XY plane
水平设定F等于常数
the level sets F equal constant that's
什么样的水平说是它的一组
what a level said is it's a set of
点x和y，其中f具有相同的值
points x and y where f has the same
价值和那些看起来像是什么
value and what do those look like let's
看到我想你认为什么是什么
see I think what do you think what are
水平集看起来像这样
the level sets look like for for this
如果我看看特别的功能
particular function if I look at the the
曲线x平方加上BY平方邪恶
curve x squared plus B Y squared evil
常数就是这个水平集
constant that's what a level set is this
是x平方加上By平方等于或
is x squared plus B y squared equal or
常量一个什么样的曲线是
constant what kind of a curve is that
这是一个椭圆形，它是什么
that's an ellipse and what's up with
那个椭圆是什么形状的呢
that ellipse what's the shape of it so
这是因为没有XY术语
it's because there's no XY term that
椭圆就好像是排成一列的
ellipse is like well lined up with the
轴是椭圆的主轴
axes the the major axes of the ellipse
是在x和y方向，因为
are on in the x and y directions because
这里没有交叉术语，我们可以
there is no cross term here and we could
如果，总是对齐我们的矩阵
always have diagonalized our matrix if
如果它不是对角线那就没有
it didn't if it wasn't diagonal and that
这不会改变任何事情
wouldn't have changed anything so this
是它只是旋转这个基地和
is it's just rotating this base and
我们做得那么好，那是什么
we've done that okay so what's the what
水平集看起来像他们
are the level sets look like they're
省略号，假设B是一个小数字
ellipses and suppose B is a small number
如果B是，那么椭圆是什么的
then what's with the ellipses if B is
小我必须去漂亮我必须采取
small I have to go pretty I have to take
一个相当大的Y来匹配X的变化
a pretty large Y to match a change in X
或者我想也许他们是省略号
or I think maybe they're ellipses of
那是他们排队等候的
that sort are they they're lined up for
轴，我希望我画画
the axes and I hope I'm drawing the
正确的方向画
right drawing on the right direction
他们是长而瘦的是对的
they're long and thin is that right
因为我不得不采取一个漂亮的
because I would have to take a pretty
大Y来弥补小B好吧
big Y to make up for a small B okay so
当我下降时会发生什么
what happens when I'm descending this
这是一个狭窄的山谷然后想到它
this is a narrow Valley then think of it
作为急剧归结在一个山谷
as a valley which comes down steeply in
Y方向但在X方向
the Y direction but in the X direction
我正在越过山谷法律那么
I'm crossing the valleys law so so what
如果我，如果我在那里采取一点哦，就会发生
happens if I if I take a point there oh
是的，我记得该怎么做
yeah I remember what to do
所以我们说，让我们在这一点上开始
so let's that let's start at that point
在那个椭圆上现在还可以
on that ellipse okay now and those were
水平设定f等于常数，那么什么
the level sets f equal constant so what
方向是什么是第一次搜索
direction what's the first search
方向我移动的方向
direction what direction do I move from
x0y0
x0 y0
我绝对沿着椭圆移动
do I move along the ellipse absolutely
不是因为它沿着椭圆而已
not because along the ellipse if it's
梯度方向是恒定的
constant the gradient direction is
垂直于你的嘴唇，所以我移动
perpendicular to your lips so I move
垂直于椭圆，何时做
perpendicular to the ellipse and when do
我很快就会停下来，因为我很快就会
I stop pretty soon because very soon I'm
再次回来，所以我开始一些
going back up again so I I start some
好吧，我不知道你是不是我
well I don't know whether you yeah I
没有练习这条曲线，但我
haven't practiced with this curve but I
知道有一次感谢上帝，但是如此
know one time's up thank God but what so
再次我知道什么是要去
once again what do I know is going to
发生在星期五，我们会成功
happen and by Friday we'll make it
发生了什么是什么是什么
happen so what's the what's what's
什么是我们看到的曲线
what's what do we see for the curve that
它的轨道说它是一个
the the track of the it's say it's a
之字形是的，如果我们愿意的话
zigzag yeah so it's if we would like to
来到这里，但我们根本不是针对这里的
get here but we're not aimed here at all
所以我们之字形曲折并且非常缓慢
so we zigzag zigzag and very slowly
接近这一点，以及如何与慢
approach that point and how slowly with
那个乘数1减去B
that with that that multiplier 1 minus B
超过1加B这就是那个
over 1 plus B so that's the that's what
我正在从这个例子中学习
I'm learning from this example that
这是一个关键数字然后你可以
that's a key number and then you could
请问一般的例子
ask well what about general examples
这是一个特别挑选的例子
this was one specially chosen example
我们会看到完全解决方案
with the exact solution well we'll see
在下一次开始的那个
at the beginning of next time that for a
凸函数这是典型的
convex function this is typical it's
这1减B是关键是
this 1 minus B is the key is the
临界数量或1超过B或如何
critical quantity or 1 over B or the how
小是B比1那么就是这样
small is B compared to 1 so that's that
将是关键数量，我们看到
will be the critical quantity and we see
它在这个比例1减去B超过1加B
it in this ratio 1 minus B over 1 plus B
所以如果B是100，这是0.99而不是1.01
so if B is 100th this is 0.99 over 1.01
它几乎是1好，所以下次是
it's virtually 1 ok so next time is a
看看我有什么关键讲座
sort of a key lecture to see what I've
刚说
just said
这是控制它的
that this is that this controls the
最陡峭的血统收敛然后
convergence of steepest descent and then
一看就知道其加速一个想法
to see an idea that speeds it up that
这个想法被称为动力或沉重
that idea is called momentum or heavy
球，所以如果你是物理的想法
ball so the physical idea is if you're
如果你想得到沉重的话
if you wanted to get if you had a heavy
球在那里，想得到它
ball right there and wanted to get it
沿着山谷向下走到你的底部
down the valley toward the bottom you
不会垂直于水平
wouldn't go perpendicular to the level
你根本没有让动力
sets not at all you let the momentum of
球接管并让它滚下来
the ball take over and let it roll down
所以动量的想法就是建模
so the the idea of momentum is to model
让这种沉重的可能性
the possibility of letting that heavy
球滚动而不是指挥它
ball roll instead of directing it by
每个点都有最陡的下降
steepest descent at every point so
最陡的一个额外的术语
there's an extra term in steepest
下降的势头转向了那个
descent the momentum turn that
accelerates it okay so Friday is the day
加速它好，所以星期五是一天
那么很高兴见到你
good see you then